# Filipe Costa da Silva Rocha

7<sup>th</sup> January 1980

Tel.: PT 960077350

Creating architectural 3d renderings since 2004. I have experience working in large and fast paced environments with tight deadlines like *Euro RSCG* – Design & Architecture, where I was responsible for delivering 2D/3D images and animations for "Sonae", "BES", "Vichy", "Peugeot". In 2008 I worked on the "Optimus" rebranding, the biggest investment in rebranding ever made at the time in Portugal. I also worked in a small architecture office and did freelancing.

In 2007 and 2008 I was invited to teach 3D Animation workshops in the Portuguese movie festival "Caminhos do cinema Português" and in late 2008 I became an ATC 3ds Max Instructor at "The edge – Digital Visual Effects Training".

I am passionate about CGI and teaching, I like keeping up to date about CG software and workflows and to be part of visual projects, from concept to end result.

**Key Skills:** 

ney Skills.	
2D	<ul> <li>Photoshop         <ul> <li>Camera Raw; Photo Manipulation; Concept Painting.</li> </ul> </li> <li>Illustrator         <ul> <li>Vector drawing and illustration; concept design;</li> </ul> </li> <li>Photography</li> </ul>
3D	<ul> <li>3Ds Max</li> <li>Modeling; Lighting; Rigging; Animation; Render.</li> <li>V-Ray; Mental Ray; FumeFX; Particles; MaxScript; Backburner.</li> <li>Mudbox</li> <li>Digital sculpting and normal map creation.</li> <li>Real Flow</li> <li>Fluids simulation.</li> </ul>
Video	<ul> <li>After effects \ Nuke</li> <li>Motion Graphics, 2D animation, Digital video effects and colour grading; video post production.</li> <li>Premiere         <ul> <li>Video editing.</li> </ul> </li> <li>Encore         <ul> <li>DVD\Blu-ray interactive menus.</li> </ul> </li> </ul>
Web	<ul> <li>Dreamweaver</li> <li>Html; CSS; Javascript.</li> <li>Flash</li> <li>Animation</li> </ul>
Other	<ul><li>Cubase – Audio production</li><li>MS Office.</li></ul>

## **Education and Training:**

Laucation and maining.	
<ul><li>I.E.F.P - Oct 2014 \ Mar 2016:</li><li>Certificate of higher education (NVQ 4)</li></ul>	INSTITUTO DO EMPREGO E FORMAÇÃO PROFISSIONAL
	Multimedia technician
<ul><li>I-zone – Sep 2011 \ Nov 2011</li><li>Certified trainer</li></ul>	k n o w l e d g e • s y s t e m s people processes technology
	Pedagogical Aptitude training course

### **Relevant experience:**

itelevant expendice.		
December 2013 – march 2014:	Project: O voo da águia ("the flight of the eagle").	
Iniziomedia Produções & LX3D Atitude Virtual	<ul> <li>responsibilities:</li> <li>Build and prepare the computers used by the vfx team.</li> <li>Coordinate and supervise the 3ds Max team.</li> <li>3D environment modelling, animation and rendering.</li> </ul>	
October 2008 – September 2011:	Role: 3ds Max instructor.	
The Edge, Digital visual effects training.	<ul> <li>Responsibilities:</li> <li>Prepare and structure 3ds Max courses for Autodesk certification.</li> <li>Lecture 3ds Max for beginners and advanced users.</li> <li>Made software presentations in job fairs and schools.</li> </ul>	
June 2007 – January 2008 and April 2012 – September 2012:	Role: 2D and 3D artist.  Projects: Optimus rebranding, Vichy package	
Euro RSCG worldwide Design & Architecture.	and stand design, Bes, peugot, continente, TMN.	
	<ul> <li>Created 2D and 3D imagery to show rebranding ideas to the client.</li> <li>Created 3D imagery for a variety of purposes and projects.</li> </ul>	

August 2000	Role:
August 2009 Fotosport	Event photographer (freelance)
September 2008 – April 2009	Role:
	3d architectural visualizer \ artist
	Project: City of Lisbon in 3D
LX3D – Atitude Virtual	Responsibilities:
	<ul> <li>3D modeling; texturing; lighting and rendering from architecture technical drawings, concept drawings and photographs</li> </ul>
2007 & 2008:	Role:
"Caminhos do cinema Português" film festival.	3d animation workshop instructor.
November 2004- January 2006:	Role:
	3d architectural visualizer
Arquitecto Luis Neto &	
Associados.	Responsibilities:
	<ul> <li>3D modeling; texturing; lighting and rendering from architecture technical drawings.</li> <li>Photography.</li> <li>Create 2D Images.</li> </ul>

#### Freelance collaborations:

Company	Project type
LX3D Atitude Virtual	Dedicated 3D Visualization Office
Ligne Roset	Interior Design
Almendra Maria Architects	Architecture Office
SIC	Golden globes stage design pre- visualization
Stamina Productions	3D and fluids animations

#### Interests:

I enjoy playing with peoples emotions through storytelling, images and sound. I am passionate about Cinema, Music and photography, studied violin as a child and now I play guitar and piano. I also enjoy reading, specially if it's science fiction or physics related. I always self improve my skills and knowledge by following online tutorials and taking courses on several subjects of interest.

Driver's licence A+B

Email: Website: Tel.: PT 960077350

<u>FilipeCSRocha@gmail.com</u> <u>filipecsrocha.github.io/</u>